Guide to the Putnam Woolen Corporation Photographs 1936
Putnam Woolen Corporation Photographs
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Putnam Woolen Corporation Photographs, 1936
6841 P
Putnam Woolen Corporation
1 file folder
Gelatin silver print, photographs.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Photographs of the March 1936, flood in Putnam, Connecticut.
1 folder
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The Putnam Woolen Corporation was established in 1878, with E. A. Wheelock as the resident agent and treasurer. The company manufactured cashmere using nineteen sets of machinery and over 300 employees.
In August 5, 1935, after six weeks on strike, about seventy employees returned to work under the guard of 15 policemen. Another 100 union workers continued picketing without incident.
By at least 1937, Putnam Woolen Corporation was a division of the Uxbridge Worsted Company, Uxbridge, Massachusetts.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Photographs of the Putnam Woolen Corporation during the March 1936 flood, in Putnam, Connecticut. Includes photographs of the exterior of the mill, the head gates, powerhouse, and weave shop.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Putnam Woolen Corporation.; Uxbridge Worsted Company
Subjects:
Disasters; Flood --1936; Flood damage; Floods; Textile factories; Textile machinery
Geographic Subjects:
Putnam (Conn.); Uxbridge (Mass.)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
RELATED MATERIALS
Related Collections:
6502 P: Amelia Olenio Collection of American Woolen Company Photographs
6610 P: Doris McLoughlin Collection of Textile Related Photographs
6794 P: Mrs. Humphreys Collection of Textile Related Photographs
CONTAINER LIST
- Putnam Woolen Flood Damage Photographs, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Rear view, Putnam Woolen Corporation during flood of 1936., black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts the rear of the Putnam Woolen Corp. during the flood of March 1936. At this point, the floodwaters have not quite reached the buildings; see item 2 in this folder for a view of the flood waters reaching the buildings. Photo taken March 13, 1936. 16.5 x 10.5 cm.
  - Item 2: Rear view, Putnam Woolen Corporation as floodwaters reach buildings., 1936; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts the rear of the Putnam Woolen Corp. during the flood of March 1936. At this point, the floodwaters have reached the buildings and have flooded at least the first floor; see item 1 in this folder for a view of just before the flood waters reached the buildings. Photo taken March 19, 1936. See item 5 in this folder for a very similar view to this one. 16.5 x 10.5 cm.
  - Item 3: Head gates, Putnam Woolen Corporation during flood of 1936., black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts the head gates of the Putnam Woolen Corp. during the flood of March 1936. The gates are in the center background; note the sandbags put in place to hold back the floodwaters from the adjacent building. See item 8 in this folder for a view of the floodwaters spilling over the gates. Photo taken March 19, 1936. 16.5 x 10.5 cm.
  - Item 4: Powerhouse, Putnam Woolen Corporation during flood of 1936., black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts the powerhouse of the Putnam Woolen Corp. during the flood of March 1936. Water appears to be level with a window; unclear if this is the first floor or higher. Water stains visible slightly higher than water level, indicating floodwaters may actually have risen higher. Photo taken March 19, 1936. 16.5 x 10.5 cm.
  - Item 5: Rear view, Putnam Woolen Corporation as floodwaters reach buildings, 1936; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts the rear of the Putnam Woolen Corp. during the flood of March 1936. At this point, the floodwaters have reached the buildings and have flooded at least the first floor; see item 1 in this folder for a view of just before the flood waters reached the buildings. Photo taken March 19, 1936. See item 2 in this folder for a very similar view to this one, taken from a slightly different angle. 16.5 x 10.5 cm.
  - Item 6: Weave shop, Putnam Woolen Corporation before floodwaters., 1936; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts the weave shop of the Putnam Woolen Corp. during the flood of March 1936. A warp beam is visible in the center of the photo. At this point, the floodwaters have not yet reached the weave shop or have just begun to flood the building; see item 7 in this folder for a view after the weave shop was flooded. Photo taken March 13, 1936. 16.5 x 10.5 cm.
  - Item 7: Weave shop, Putnam Woolen Corporation after floodwaters., 1936; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts the weave shop of the Putnam Woolen Corp. after the flood of March 1936. Water is visible on the floor and some machinery has been submerged; see item 6 in this folder for a view before the weave shop was flooded. Photo taken March 19, 1936. 16.5 x 10.5 cm.
  - Item 8: Water spilling over head gates, Putnam Woolen Corporation during flood of 1936., black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts floodwaters spilling over the head gates of the Putnam Woolen Corp. during the flood of March 1936. Writing on reverse indicates that the final height was about six inches more. See item 3 in this folder for a view of the gates from above. Photo taken March 19, 1936. 16.5 x 10.5 cm.
  - Item 9: View of floodwaters from mill building, Putnam Woolen Corporation during flood of 1936., black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts a view of the floodwaters up against one of the mill buildings of the Putnam Woolen Corp. during the flood of March 1936. Water is up to the windows; unclear if this is a first floor window. Photo taken March 19, 1936. 16.5 x 10.5 cm.